### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ deniskamotsky (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Python (Programming Language)
Natural Language Processing (NLP)
Search Relevance

## Languages

Russian (Native or Bilingual)

#### **Patents**

System and method for performing a multiple pass search

Method for calculating relevancy scores of search results

System and method for performing a pattern matching search

Systems and methods for calculating recommendation scores based on combined signals from multiple recommendation systems

System and method for performing a multiple pass search

# **Denis Kamotsky**

Principal Software Engineer | Advanced Analytics at Corning Incorporated

Santa Fe, New Mexico, United States

## Summary

Over 20 years of professional experience in software architecture, design, development, and support. Specializing in E-Commerce, Information Retrieval, and Machine Learning applications.

Proven engineering thought leader at macys\*com, the largest online fashion retailer in the United States, and #14 online retailer globally. Delivered countless projects, contributing to the online sales growth from \$200M in 2001 to nearly \$6B in 2019. Arrived in e-commerce from the background in computational linguistics research. Architected, designed, and built macys\*com's Keyword Search and Product Discovery platforms. Implemented original engineering solutions covered by multiple U.S. patents. In the last four years delivered value by applying machine learning to e-commerce, primarily focusing on natural language processing, computer vision, and recommendation systems. Played all SDLC roles over the 19 years career at macys\*com: hands-on developer (Java, Python), data scientist, technical lead, onshore/offshore delivery lead, software architect, domain architect, product manager.

# Experience

Corning Incorporated

Principal Software Engineer | Advanced Analytics | Emerging Technologies

June 2020 - Present (2 years 11 months)

Santa Fe, New Mexico, United States

Helping researchers, data scientists, and technologists build and scale cloudenabled machine learning pipelines. Promoting modern software development practices in the world of advanced analytics. Databricks, PySpark, Dask, Tensorflow, Kubernetes, AWS.

Macy's Principal Engineer January 2001 - March 2020 (19 years 3 months) San Francisco Bay Area

Proven engineering thought leader at macys\*com, the largest online fashion retailer in the United States, and #14 online retailer globally. Delivered countless projects, contributing to the online sales growth from \$200M in 2001 to nearly \$6B in 2019. Arrived in e-commerce from the background in computational linguistics research. Architected, designed, and built macys\*com's Keyword Search and Product Discovery platforms. Implemented original engineering solutions covered by multiple U.S. patents. In the last four years delivered value by applying machine learning to e-commerce, primarily focusing on natural language processing, computer vision, and recommendation systems. Played all SDLC roles over the 19 years career at macys\*com: hands-on developer (Java, Python), data scientist, technical lead, onshore/offshore delivery lead, software architect, domain architect, product manager.

New Mexico State University
Research Assistant
October 1997 - January 2001 (3 years 4 months)
Las Cruces, New Mexico Area

Supported leading scientists in the field of Computational Linguistics to help build innovative (at the time) machine translation and natural language processing systems for DARPA.

## Education

South Ural State University (SUSU)

Diplom (Master's), Applied Mathematics · (1993 - 1998)